Worrying mind, perfectionist mind
(Questioner) Hello! I tend to
think and worry too much.
I worry about things that
have not happened yet.
Most of my anxiety revolves around
interpersonal relationships.
I didn't have this problem
while I was working.
I would say what I had to say,
hear what I was told, and avoid
(Questioner) those I didn't care for.
No conflict with other people.
(Questioner) But since I got married,
as you mentioned earlier,
(Questioner) I have to deal with a
number of other people in tow.
(Questioner) Even before our marriage,
(Questioner) our strong personalities
drove us to fights often.
Now, my husband offers me little comfort.
I tend to get hurt a lot by
other people over small things.
Though I feel relieved after
an event that I hosted,
I am already worried about my
mom's 60th birthday party next year.
"Should I do this, or that?"
"How can I avoid getting criticized
and get approval from family?"
These thoughts trouble me a lot.
So, how can I change my
thoughts to be more positive
so that I can relax? Please tell me
what I can do about this?
(Sunim) It's simple. Starting today, pray
"I am willing to accept criticisms."
Trying to avoid criticism
causes you stress.
Just accept the criticisms
and be undaunted.
I wish I could do that..
(Sunim) But what?
(Questioner) I wish I could but...
when I hear someone say..
That is why I tell you to pray.
Repeat, "I accept all the
criticisms." while you prostrate.
You know the saying,
"getting lots of criticisms while
doing good work will give you a long life"
(Questioner) "Yes.
It's a blessing to receive criticisms.
Your life span will extend every time
you receive one. (Audience Laughter)
So, pray for more criticisms.
(Questioner) Yes, I see. Thank you.
This is also known as " Reap what you sow"
(Questioner) Yes.
"I accept criticisms," is
putting it bluntly.
Putting it a bit elegantly is what?
I will reap what I sow.
I will accept gladly what I sow.
So, just accept everything as they come.
(Questioner) Yes, I will do that.
You must prostrate when you pray.
Praying by itself is not enough.
Do a lot of prostrations.
(Questioner) Yes.
If you continue to worry too much,
the anxiety will lead to mental illness.
Not only will you suffer but also this will
have an adverse affect on your children.
Starting now, just accept
criticisms with ease.
Understand that others have their
own reasons to criticize you.
Just accept them with ease.
Yes, thank you. (Applause)
(Sunim) Do a lot of prostrations.
Whenever you have time, do prostrations.
Sensitive and anxious people
need to do a lot of prostrations.